Guide to the Bebe Moore Campbell Papers, 1956-2008 SC.2017.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Bebe Moore Campbell Papers
1956-2008
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Campbell, Bebe Moore
SC.2017.02
12.18 Linear Feet (29 document cases)
Bebe Moore Campbell was an award-winning author, journalist, teacher and playwright whose professional works reflected the African-American experience in the United States. A native of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, Campbell graduated from the University of Pittsburgh in 1971. Several of her fictional works appeared in New York Times bestsellers lists. The papers document Bebe Moore Campbell's professional life with specific focus on the creative and administrative process of publishing in the late 20th and early 21st century. Included are many drafts and revisions of her writings as well as contracts, correspondence, reviews, promotional activities and rankings of her works.
Access Restrictions
No Restriction.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated to the University of Pittsburgh by Ellis Gordon in December, 2017.
Arrangement
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Manuscripts and Screenplays
Series III: Articles about Bebe Moore Campbell
Series IV: Writings by others
Series V: Book Reviews and Rankings
Series VI: Organizations
Series VII: Promotional Activities
Series VIII: Tour Schedules
Series IX: Contracts
Series X: Financials
Series XI: Personal Papers
Biography
Bebe Moore Campbell was born Elizabeth Bebe Moore on February 18, 1950 in Philadelphia Pennsylvania. An only child, her parents Doris Edwina Carter Moore and George Linwood Peter Moore divorced three years after her birth. During the school year her mother, aunt, and maternal grandmother raised Campbell in Philadelphia, while she spent her summers with her father in North Carolina. After graduating from Philadelphia's Girls High School, she went on to attend the University of Pittsburgh, where she graduated summa cum laude with a Bachelor of Science in elementary education in 1971.
During her time at Pitt, Campbell was involved with the early days of the Black Action Society, an organization that she maintained interest in and contact with throughout her life. This is also when she married her first husband, her high school boyfriend Tiko Campbell, who she divorced in 1979. The couple had one child together, Maia Campbell, who later went on to become an actor.
Campbell moved to Atlanta and then Washington D.C. to teach elementary school for several years, before she began to pursue a career in writing in the mid-to-late 1970s. Starting as a freelance journalist, Campbell wrote articles for many well-known publications, including the New York Times, Washington Post, Essence, Los Angeles Times, and Ebony. Campbell also appeared on National Public Radio (NPR) as a commentator on Morning Edition. In 1984, she married Ellis Gordon Jr., who she would stay with until her death in 2006. The couple raised their two children (Maia and Ellis Gordon III, who was born from Gordon's previous marriage) in Los Angeles, California.
In 1986, Campbell published her first book; a non-fiction work entitled Successful Women, Angry Men: Backlash in the Two-Career Marriage. Her next work was a semi-autobiographical book about her childhood, Sweet Summer: Growing Up with and without My Dad, which was published in 1989.
Campbell's work touched on subjects and themes important to her, such as racial justice, childhood obesity, and mental illness. Her first novel, Your Blues Ain't Like Mine (1992), discussed a fictionalized version of the death of Emmett Till, a black teenager who was murdered for speaking in a suggestive manner to a white woman in Mississippi. Another book, Brothers and Sisters (1994) is set in Los Angeles in the aftermath of the Rodney King verdict. Other well-known works from Campbell include Singing in the Comeback Choir (1998), about a successful businesswoman who returns to her childhood Philadelphia neighborhood at the request of her aging grandmother's caretaker, What You Owe Me (2001), about the friendship and betrayal between a black hotel maid and Jewish Holocaust survivor who start a business together, and 72 Hour Hold, about a mother trying to come to grips with her daughter's mental illness.
In addition to her writing for adults, Campbell also published multiple children's books. These include Sometimes My Mommy Gets Angry (2003), which tackles a child's view of her mother's mental illness, Stompin' at the Savoy (2006), a story about a girl who gets magically transported to the famous jazz club, and I Get So Hungry (2008), which describes a child's struggle with obesity. Campbell also authored two radio plays, "Sugar on the Floor" and "Old Lady Shoes".
Campbell died from brain cancer on November 27, 2006, at age 56. She is buried in Inglewood Park Cemetery in Inglewood, California. For her writings, she received three New York Times best sellers, Los Angeles Times "Best Book of 2001", New York Times Notable Book of the Year, and the NAACP Image Award for Literature.
Scope and Content Notes
The Bebe Moore Campbell papers contain correspondence, drafts and revisions of various novels and articles, contracts, book reviews, publicity, promotional materials, research files and tour schedules that document the creative and administrative process of Bebe Moore Campbell, a late 20th and early 21st century author who was successful in publishing and promoting her works to a wide audience.
Book reviews; Correspondence; Financial records; Manuscripts (Document genre); Manuscripts for publication; African American authors; African American authors -- Fiction; African Americans authors -- Juvenile fiction; African American dramatists; African American journalists; African American journalists -- Periodicals; African American journalists -- Social conditions; Women authors, American -- 21th century; Women authors, American -- 20th century; Mental health literature; African-American literature and culture; Campbell, Bebe Moore; Gordon, Ellis, Jr.; Campbell, Maia Chinassa
- Correspondence, 1992-2006; I.
  - General Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, Jan. 1995 - May 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, Jun. 1995 - Aug. 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, Sep. 1995 - Dec. 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, Jan. 1996 - Mar. 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, Apr. 1996 - Aug. 1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, Sep. 1996 - Dec. 1996 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, Jan. 1997 - May 1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, Jun. 1997 - Dec. 1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, Jan. 1998 - Mar. 1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, Apr. 1998 - Aug. 1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, Sep. 1998 - Dec. 1998 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, Jan. 1999 - Jun. 1999 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, Aug. 1999 - Dec. 1999 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - General Correspondence, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - General Correspondence, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - General Correspondence, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - General Correspondence, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - General Correspondence, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Fanmail, 1992 - 1995 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Fanmail, 1995 - 2005 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Jenner Academy Letters, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Book Club Letters, 1994 - 1997 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Manuscripts and Screenplays, 1977-2005; II.
  - Where I Useta Live, c1995 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Summary, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Draft (Chapters 1-8), 1997 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Draft (Chapters 9-15), 1997 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Draft (Chapters 16-21), 1997 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Draft (Chapters 22-25), 1997 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 1-7), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 8-13), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 14-20), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 21-25), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 1-7), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 8-12), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 13-18), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 19-26), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 1-7), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 8-13), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 14-20), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 21-26), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 1-6), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 7-12), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 13-21), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 21-26), 1997 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft Edits, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 1-8), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 9-13), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 14-19), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 20-26), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Edited Draft (Chapters 1-6), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Edited Draft (Chapters 7-10), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Edited Draft (Chapters 11-16), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Edited Draft (Chapters 17-23), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Edited Draft (Chapters 24-26), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Various Edits, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Draft (Chapter 1), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Draft (Chapter 1-4), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Draft (Chapter 5-7), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Draft (Chapter 8-9), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Draft (Chapter 10-14), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Draft (Chapter 15-18), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Draft (Chapter 19-22), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Draft (Chapter 23-26), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revision Notes, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 1-4), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 5-8), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, Revised Draft (Chapters 9-13), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - What You Owe Me, Proof, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - What You Owe Me, Draft (Chapters 1-3), 2000 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - What You Owe Me, Draft (Chapters 34-38), 2000 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - What You Owe Me, Draft (Chapters 39-46), 2000 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - What You Owe Me, Draft (Chapters 47-57), 2000 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - What You Owe Me, Draft (Chapters 58-67), 2000 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - I Remember Normal, Notes, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - I Remember Normal, Draft, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - I Remember Normal, Revised Synopsis, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - I Remember Normal, Revised Draft, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - I Remember Normal, Edited Draft, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - I Remember Normal, Edited Draft, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - I Remember Normal, Revised Draft, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - I Remember Normal, Notes, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - The Rhumba Girl, Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Going Places, Draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Friends and Lovers, Draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Bruised, Act 1 Draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Bruised, Draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Bruised, Draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Bruised, Draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - Bruised, Draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - Bruised, Edited Draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Bruised, Revised Draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Bruised, Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Sugar on the Floor, Draft, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Sugar on the Floor, Draft, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - Old Lady Shoes, Printed Draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Summary, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 102)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Draft (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Edited Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Edited Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Edited Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 108)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 109)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 110)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Edited Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Edited Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Edited Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 114)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Edited Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Draft, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 116)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Draft (Scene II), 2002 (Box 12, Folder 117)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Edited Draft, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 118)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Edited Draft, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 119)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Edited Draft, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 120)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Edited Draft, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 121)
  - Crazy/Even With the Madness, Draft, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 122)
  - 72 Hour Hold, Audio Recording Draft (Pages 1-70), 2005 (Box 12, Folder 123)
  - 72 Hour Hold, Audio Recording Draft (Pages 70-132), 2005 (Box 12, Folder 124)
  - 72 Hour Hold, Audio Recording Draft (Pages 133-185), 2005 (Box 12, Folder 125)
  - Sometimes Mommy Gets Angry, Proofs, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 126)
  - Sometimes Mommy Gets Anrgy, Draft, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 127)
  - Sometimes Mommy Gets Angry, Notes, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 128)
  - I Get So Hungary, Printed Proofs, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 129)
  - Stompin' at the Savoy, Printed Proofs, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 130)
  - "Carrying On", undated (Box 12, Folder 131)
  - "Cloakroom Incident", undated (Box 12, Folder 132)
  - "Come on in if you Can Swim Through Dust", undated (Box 12, Folder 133)
  - "Deliverance from Evil", undated (Box 12, Folder 134)
  - "Half Stepping Housekeeping", undated (Box 12, Folder 135)
  - "Loss of Innocence", 2005 (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - "Playing the Game", undated (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - "The Potty Con", undated (Box 12, Folder 138)
  - "Scent of Peaches", undated (Box 12, Folder 139)
  - "Searching for Roots", undated (Box 12, Folder 140)
  - "Shades of Black", undated (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - "A Shopping Trip", undated (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - "Superman, Batman, and Me, " Essence, November, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - Bebe's Corner Scripts, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 144)
  - Segments, Morning Edition on National Public Radio, c1993-2005 (Box 13, Folder 145)
  - Segments, Morning Edition on National Public Radio, c1993-2005 (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1980-1995 (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Magazine Articles, 1992-1998 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - Magazine Articles, 1999-2002 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Magazine Articles, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - Magazine Articles, 2004-2005 (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - Writing Notes, Bound Journals, undated (Box 13, Folder 152)
  - Writing Notes, Loose, undated (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - Speech Notes, Loose, undated (Box 14, Folder 154)
  - Speeches, Handwritten, undated (Box 14, Folder 155)
  - Speeches, Typed, undated (Box 14, Folder 156)
  - Speeches, Typed, undated (Box 14, Folder 157)
  - "Mothers" Poems, Draft, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 158)
  - "Mothers" Poems, Introduction, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 159)
  - Poetry Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 160)
  - Poems, Loose, undated (Box 14, Folder 161)
  - Poems, Loose, undated (Box 14, Folder 162)
  - Writing Notes, Loose, undated (Box 14, Folder 163)
- Articles on Bebe Moore Campbell, 1991-2006; III.
  - Newspaper Articles, Undated (Box 15, Folder 164)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 165)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 166)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 167)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 168)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1996-1997 (Box 15, Folder 169)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 170)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1999-2003 (Box 16, Folder 171)
  - Newspaper Articles, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 172)
  - Newspaper Articles, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 173)
  - Magazine Articles, 1992-1994 (Box 16, Folder 174)
  - Magazine Articles, 1995-1997 (Box 16, Folder 175)
  - Magazine Articles, 1997-2006 (Box 16, Folder 176)
  - Maia Campbell Newspaper Articles, 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 177)
  - Maia Campbell Magazine Articles, 1993-1997 (Box 17, Folder 178)
  - Maia Campbell Magazine Articles, 1997-2004 (Box 17, Folder 179)
- Research and Writings by Others, 1956-2006; IV.
  - Research, Mental Health, 1995-2005 (Box 17, Folder 180)
  - Research, Mental Health, 1996-2001 (Box 17, Folder 181)
  - Research, Terrie Williams, 2003-2005 (Box 17, Folder 182)
  - Research, Personal Inspiration, 1998-2003 (Box 17, Folder 183)
  - Research, Writing, c2000-2004 (Box 17, Folder 184)
  - Research, Race, 1992-2006 (Box 17, Folder 185)
  - Research, Other, 1996-1998 (Box 17, Folder 186)
  - Research, Other, 1992.1998 (Box 18, Folder 187)
  - Research, Other (Box 18, Folder 188)
  - "Somebody's Got to be in Charge" by Leslie E. Clapp, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 189)
  - "Somebody's Got to be in Charge" by Leslie E. Clapp, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 190)
  - "Somebody's Got to be in Charge" by Leslie E. Clapp, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 191)
  - "Crazy - A Father's Search Through America's Mental Health Madness" by Peter Earley, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 192)
  - "Crazy - A Father's Search Through America's Mental Health Madness" by Peter Earley, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 193)
  - "Crazy - A Father's Search Through America's Mental Health Madness", by Peter Earley, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 194)
  - Student Treatments of You're Blues Ain't Like Mine, undated (Box 18, Folder 195)
  - "Through Oppression Lies Victory" by Ryan Halvorson, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 196)
  - Your Blues Ain't Like Mine, Screen Treatment by Georgia Jeffries, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 197)
  - Your Blues Ain't Like Mine, Screen Treatment by Georgia Jeffries (Third Draft), 1997 (Box 19, Folder 198)
  - "Sugar - A Novel" by Bernice L. McFadden, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - "Sugar - A Novel" by Bernice L. McFadden, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 200)
  - "Sugar - A Novel" by Bernice L. McFadden, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 201)
  - "Sugar - A Novel" by Bernice L. McFadden, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 202)
  - "The Condemnation of Little B" by Elaine Brown, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 203)
  - "Ruby McCollum, the Woman in the Suwannee Jail" by William Bradford Huie, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 204)
  - "Vista Clara" teleplay by Georgia Jeffries, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 205)
  - "Gold Rush" notes, undated (Box 19, Folder 206)
- Book Reviews and Rankings, 1993-2005; V.
  - Book Ranking Charts, 1993-1998 (Box 20, Folder 207)
  - Book Ranking Charts, 1998-2005 (Box 20, Folder 208)
  - Newspaper Book Reviews, 1993-1995 (Box 20, Folder 209)
  - Newspaper Book Reviews, 1996-2002 (Box 20, Folder 210)
  - Newspaper Book Reviews, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 211)
- Organizations, 1978-2006; VI.
  - Mississippi University For Women, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 212)
  - Black Issues, 1997-2001 (Box 20, Folder 213-214)
  - National Alliance for the Mentally Ill (NAMI), 2002-2006 (Box 21, Folder 215-216)
  - National Alliance for the Mentally Ill, "NAMI Walks", 2005 (Box 21, Folder 217)
  - River Community, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 218)
  - California Institute for Mental Health, 2000-2004 (Box 21, Folder 219)
  - Life Adjustment Team, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 220)
  - Mental Health Organizations, Assorted, 1999-2005 (Box 21, Folder 221)
  - African American Organizations, Assorted, 1994-2005 (Box 21, Folder 222)
  - The Association of Black Psychologists, Inc., 2000 (Box 21, Folder 223)
  - The Zora Neale Hurston/Richard Wright Foundation, 1996-1997 (Box 21, Folder 224)
  - The National Coaltion of 100 Black Women, Inc. Pennsylvania Chapter Directory, 2004-2005 (Box 21, Folder 225)
  - Personal Events, 1994-2000 (Box 21, Folder 226)
  - Virginia State University, 1999-2000 (Box 22, Folder 227)
  - Academic Institutions, Assorted, 1997-1999 (Box 22, Folder 228)
  - Philadelphia High School for Girls, 1998-2005 (Box 22, Folder 229)
  - Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, 1996-2006 (Box 22, Folder 230)
  - Youth Organizations, Assorted, 1978-1999 (Box 22, Folder 231)
  - Piney Woods School, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 232)
  - Mental Health Alternatives to Solitary Confinement, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 233)
  - Religious Organizations, Assorted, 1992-2006 (Box 22, Folder 234)
  - Edison International, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 235)
  - Essence Musical Festival, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 236)
  - Los Angeles Public Library, 1996-1999 (Box 22, Folder 237)
  - Society of Children's Book Writers & Illustrators, Roster, 2003-2004 (Box 22, Folder 238)
  - Central Texas African American Family Support Conference, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 239)
  - Los Angeles Times, 2000-2005 (Box 23, Folder 240)
  - Literary Organizations, Assorted, 1993-2005 (Box 23, Folder 241)
  - Mothers Reclaiming Our Children, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 242)
  - Great Beginnings for Black Babies, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 243)
  - National Speakers Association, 2005-2006 (Box 23, Folder 244)
  - The International IMPAC Dublin Literary Award, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 245)
  - The History Makers, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 246)
  - Our Texas, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 247)
  - Turner Broadcasting System Inc., 1998 (Box 23, Folder 248)
  - Leadership Organizations, Assorted, 1999-2006 (Box 23, Folder 249)
  - Norwood Security Consultants, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 250)
  - The Book Bridge Project, undated (Box 23, Folder 251)
  - The Dorothy Height Legacy Initiative, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 252)
  - Treatment Advocacy Center, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 253)
  - University of Pittsburgh, Blue, Gold, & Black, 2004-2006 (Box 23, Folder 254-255)
- Promotional Activities, 1989-2005; VII.
  - Sweet Summer, c1989 (Box 24, Folder 256)
  - Your Blues Ain't Like Mine, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 257)
  - Brothers and Sisters, 1993-1994 (Box 24, Folder 258)
  - Singing in the Comeback Choir, 1997-1998 (Box 24, Folder 259)
  - What You Owe Me, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 260)
  - 72 Hour Hold, 2004-2005 (Box 24, Folder 261)
  - Even With the Madness, 2003 (Box 24, Folder 262)
  - Sometimes Mommy Gets Angry, 2003-2005 (Box 24, Folder 263)
  - Publicity, Assorted, 1995-1996 (Box 24, Folder 264)
- Tour Schedules, 1993-2005; VIII.
  - Tour Schedule, Undated (Box 25, Folder 265)